Muhammad Fathir Irhas

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · BACKEND DEVELOPER

Jakarta - Tangerang

□ (+62) 812-2444-1284 | ▼ fathir.irhas@outlook.com | ★ mfathirirhas.github.io | □ mfathirirhas | □ mfathirirhas

Summary _

Software Engineer in **backend** development well versed in **Go Programming Language** and other tools related. Experienced in **microservices** architecture. **Fundamental** with principles. Sometime opinionated. Always learning to improve skills. Able to work individually or in team. Trying to achieve solutions with best possible way and practices.

Education

Telkom University

Bandung, Indonesia

Sarjana Komputer(S.Kom) 2012 - 2016

Experience

Tiket.com Jakarta, Indonesia

Backend Engineer Nov 2020 - Present

· Working in Flight Prepurchase team.

- Tech stacks: Go, Java Spring, MongoDB, Redis, Kafka, RabbitMQ, etc.
- · Creating internal mock server for mocking part of inter-services communications, especially partner and integration with flight supplier.
- Working on flight search caching tools to populate search cache preemptively

TokopediaJakarta, Indonesia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jul 2018 - April 2020

- Use Golang, Javascript, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, NSQ, gRPC, and GQL.
- Contribute in Saldo Tokopedia, Internal Tools, and some investment products.
- Contribute in Saldo Tokopedia Saldo Penghasilan separation.
- Revamp Saldo Tokopedia legacy front end.
- Rewrite Saldo Tokopedia legacy codebase to implement interface based development and creating testable code.
- Implement unit tests.
- Develop services doing CRUD in PostgreSQL and MySQL as persistence and Redis as cache.
- Develop APIs in REST, gRPC, and GQL.
- Develop message queue using NSQ.
- Develop cron for task scheduling.
- Create EGold(Tokopedia Emas) metrics monitoring in datadog.
- Monitor services from datadog, prometheus, and server log.
- Collaborate with other team to provide interface and integration to/from Fintech's products/services.
- Migrate some legacy internal API from Perl to Golang.
- Execute tickets coming from users through ops team relating to issues in products.

Anabatic Technologies

Serpong Tangerang, Indonesia

Jan 2018 - Jun 2018

- TECHNICAL CONSULTANT
- Monitor client's app runningSupport product development and customization

Emporia Digital Raya, Anabatic Technologies

Serpong Tangerang, Indonesia

Nov 2016 - Dec 2017

SOFTWARE ENGINEER(JUNIOR)

- · Work in Agile running sprint every 2 weeks.
- Maintain Main site.
- Develop UI components using HTML, CSS, Javascript, and JSP.
- Develop web services in form of REST APIs, firebase push notif, mail services, authentication for mobile apps using PHP, Java and MySQL.
- · Versioning and deployment.

Skill

Main

GO, POSTGRESQL, MYSQL, MONGODB, CACHE, GRPC, GRAPHQL, HTTP, MESSAGE QUEUE, DOCKER, TESTING

Lesser:

Java, Javascript, HTML

Other_

Blog: https://mfathirirhas.github.io/blog
More: https://mfathirirhas.github.io/resume
Portfolio: https://mfathirirhas.github.io/portfolio
*note: I rarely updated my blog. I planned to update it anytime soon.